A Guide to the Equal Suffrage League Collection, 1909-1938
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records, 1909-1938
Library of Virginia
22002
17.43 cu. ft. (22 boxes)
Equal Suffrage League
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Box 5, Folders 346-354 are fragile, serve duplicates only.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ida Mae Thompson, 1942.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Equal Suffrage League of Virginia was formed in 1909 by a small group of Richmond activists. The League elected Lila Meade Valentine as its president and included writers Ellen Glasgow and Mary Johnston, artists Adele Clark and Nora Houston, and Dr. Kate Waller Barrett among its members. Through canvassing, distributing leaflets, and public speaking, the Equal Suffrage League intended to educate Virginias citizens and legislators and win their support for womens suffrage. Nearly 120 members joined during the Leagues first year of existence.
By 1911, state headquarters for the Equal Suffrage League had been established in Richmond. Despite the fact that the League was one of the most vital suffrage organizations in the South, womens suffrage resolutions were defeated in the Virginia legislature in 1914 and 1916. After the 1916 defeat, Virginia suffragists worked primarily for the passage of a federal amendment. Membership in the League grew dramatically from 9,662 in 1916 to nearly 16,000 in 1917. By the time the Nineteenth Amendment was passed by Congress in June 1919, the Equal Suffrage League boasted 30,000 members.
Despite the efforts of the Equal Suffrage League, Virginia was one of the nine southern states which refused to grant the vote to women. Within a few weeks of the national victory in 1920, the Equal Suffrage League disbanded. The Virginia League of Women Voters, as its successor, shortly afterwards began work to make the new vote an informed one. Virginia did not ratify the Nineteenth Amendment until 1952.
For a description of the suffrage movement in Virginia, see Carol Jean Clare, The Woman Suffrage Movement in Virginia: its Nature, Rationale, and Tactics (M.A., University of Virginia, 1968); Sara Hunter Graham, Woman Suffrage in Virginia: the Equal Suffrage League and Pressure Group Politics, 1909-1920, Virginia Magazine of History and Biography, 101 (April 1993): 227-250; Trudy Jean Hamner, A Divine Discontent: Mary Johnston and Woman Suffrage in Virginia (M.A., University of Virginia, 1972); Charlotte Jean Shelton, Woman Suffrage and Virginia Politics, 1909-1920 (M.A., University of Virginia 1969); and Marjorie Spruill Wheeler, New Women of the New South: the Leaders of the Woman Suffrage Movement in the Southern States (Ph.D., University of Virginia, 1990).
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1909-1938, of the Equal Suffrage League of Virginia. Includes correspondence, organization records for both the Equal Suffrage League and the League of Women Voters, printed materials, newspaper clippings, "Votes for Women" buttons, and postcards. The publications relate to womens suffrage and related issues of government, organization, education, child and economic welfare, and the legal status of women. The collections correspondence includes a sizable number of letters by Jessie Townsend and Mary Elizabeth Pidgeon, along with those of Adele Clark, Edith Clark Cowles, and Lila Meade Valentine.
The collection was received by the Virginia State Library in 1942 from Ida Mae Thompson, a clerk with the WPA Historical Records Survey. Thompson had previously served as office secretary for the Equal Suffrage League and the League of Women Voters.
The researcher is advised to consult the finding aid before examining the records. Due to the artificial nature of the collection, certain types of material will appear in more than one location, with original order taking precedence; for example, Ida Thompsons Historic Records Survey requests for information on local suffrage leagues are filed in Box 3 by locality, along with letters and materials sent in response, while the majority of correspondence is filed chronologically in Boxes 1 and 2.
The suffrage crusade was complementary to other reform movements of the early twentieth century. While mobilized to win the vote, suffragists fought for changes in child labor laws and food and drug regulations. When the United States entered World War I in 1917, the League directed their efforts to patriotic relief, advocating domestic food production and seeking subscribers for Liberty Loans. The materials in the Equal Suffrage League collection reflect this diversity of effort.
Related collections in the Virginia State Library and Archives include the organization records of the League of Women Voters, 1950-1970 (Accession 27804). Additional related collections are at the Virginia Historical Society (Adele Clark Papers, Houston Papers, and Lila Meade Valentine Papers) and the Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University (Adele Clark Papers).
Arrangement
Much of the original order of the Equal Suffrage League collection has been lost. Where possible, the processors maintained the order established and noted by Thompson. Elsewhere, the processors supplied an order that seemed most consistent with the evidence available.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1909-1933 (Box 1, Folder 1-55)
- Correspondence, undated and fragile (Box 2, Folder 56-60)
- Historical Records Survey (Inquiries and Responses, 1936-1937)
  - Accomack County (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Albemarle County (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Albemarle County, University Equal Suffrage League (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Amelia County (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Amherst County (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Appomattox County (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Arlington County (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Bath County (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Bedford County (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Brunswick County (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Buchanan County (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Buckingham County (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Campbell County (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Campbell County, Randolph-Macon Equal Suffrage League (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Caroline County (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Carroll County (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Charles City County (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Charlotte County (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Chesterfield County (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Clarke County (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Culpeper County (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Cumberland County (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Essex County (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Fairfax County (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Fauquier County (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Floyd County (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Fluvanna County (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Gloucester County (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Giles County (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Goochland County (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Grayson County (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Halifax County (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Henrico County (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Henrico County, Westhampton College (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Henry County (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Isle of Wight County (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - King George County (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Lancaster County (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Loudoun County (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Louisa County (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Lunenburg County (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Mecklenburg County (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Middlesex County (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Montgomery County (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Nelson County (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - New Kent County (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Northampton County (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Orange County (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Patrick County (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Prince George County (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Princess Anne County (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Pulaski County (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Rappahannock County (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Richmond County (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Roanoke County (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Southampton County (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Surry County (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Sussex County (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Tazewell County (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Washington County (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - York County (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Ashland (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Big Stone Gap (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Boydton (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Burkeville (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Chatham (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Claremont (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Clarksville (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Clifton Forge (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Covington (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Danville (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Emporia (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Farmville (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Fredericksburg (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Front Royal (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Graham (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Hampton (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Harrisonburg (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Heathsville (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Highland Springs (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Irvington (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Jamestown (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Lexington (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Lynchburg (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Manassas (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Marion (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Martinsville (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Monterey (Box 3, Folder 147a)
  - Newport News (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - Norfolk (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - Norfolk (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - Norfolk (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - Norfolk (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - Norfolk (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - Norfolk (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - Norfolk (Box 3, Folder 155)
  - Norfolk, Jessie Townsend, notes and drafts (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - Norfolk, Jessie Townsend, notes and drafts (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - Norfolk, Jessie Townsend, undated correspondence (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - Norton (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - Petersburg (Box 3, Folder 160)
  - Portsmouth (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - Richmond (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - Rocky Mount (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - Salem (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - Saluda (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - Shawsville (Box 3, Folder 166)
  - South Hill (Box 3, Folder 167)
  - Staunton (Box 3, Folder 168)
  - Suffolk (Box 3, Folder 169)
  - Urbana (Box 3, Folder 170)
  - Warrenton (Box 3, Folder 171)
  - West Point (Box 3, Folder 172)
  - Williamsburg (Box 3, Folder 173)
  - Winchester (Box 3, Folder 174)
  - Woodstock (Box 3, Folder 175)
  - Wytheville (Box 3, Folder 176)
- Organization Records, Equal Suffrage League, National
  - Pledges, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 177)
- Organization Records, Equal Suffrage League, Virginia
  - Annual Meeting Reports, 1910-1919 (Box 4, Folder 178)
  - Ballots, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 179)
  - Committe reports, 1912-1919 (Box 4, Folder 180)
  - Committe reports, nd (Box 4, Folder 181)
  - Constitution (Box 4, Folder 182)
  - Convention Delegates and Board Minutes, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 183)
  - Convention Delegates, including League of Women Voters, 1914-1920 (Box 4, Folder 183a)
  - Convention minutes, 1916-1917 (Box 4, Folder 184)
  - Convention reports, 1911-1918 (Box 4, Folder 185)
  - Convention report, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 186)
  - Convention report, Equal Suffrage League Histories, 1910-1919 (Box 4, Folder 187)
  - Financial (Box 4, Folder 188)
  - Financial (Box 4, Folder 189)
  - History, drafts and correspondence, 1919-1922 (Box 4, Folder 190)
  - Legislative committee, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 191)
  - Legislative committee, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 192)
  - Legislative committee, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 193)
  - Legislative committee, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 195)
  - Legislative committee, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 196)
  - Legislative committee, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 197)
  - Legislative committee, nd (Box 4, Folder 198)
  - Legislative Committee, Federal Amendment File, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 199)
  - Legislative Committee, General Assembly, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 200)
  - Legislative Committee, General Assembly, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 201)
  - Legislative Committee, General Assembly, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 202)
  - Legislative Committee, General Assembly, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 203)
  - Legislative Committee, General Assembly, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 204)
  - Legislative Committee, General Assembly, nd (Box 4, Folder 205)
  - Legislative Committee, Presidential Suffrage File, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 206)
  - Letters to the editor, 1913-1920 (Box 4, Folder 207)
  - Meeting agendas (Box 4, Folder 208)
  - Meeting reports, 1909-1910 (Box 4, Folder 209)
  - Meeting reports, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 210)
  - Meeting reports, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 211)
  - Meeting reports, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 212)
  - Minutes of the Executive Council, Executive Committee, Executive Board, State Board, 1914-1918 (Box 4, Folder 213)
  - Minuts of the state convention, 1911-1913 (Box 4, Folder 214)
  - Presidents annual report, 1918-1919 (Box 4, Folder 215)
  - Presidents survey, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 216)
  - Reports of Corresponding secretary, Executive secretary, Headquarters Reports, 1912-1914 (Box 4, Folder 217)
  - Reports of Corresponding secretary, Executive secretary, Headquarters Reports, 1915-1920 (Box 4, Folder 218)
  - Secretarys report to annual coventions, 1913-1916 (Box 4, Folder 219)
  - Treasurers reports, 1912-1917 (Box 4, Folder 220)
  - Members, 1912-1916 (Box 4, Folder 221)
  - Membership lists, Localities A-E, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 222)
  - Membership lists, Localities F-H, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 223)
  - Membership lists, Localities I-M, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 224)
  - Membership lists, Localities N-W, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 225)
  - Members, male, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 226)
  - Members, Carroll County (Box 4, Folder 227)
  - Members, Greensville County (Box 4, Folder 228)
  - Members, Loudoun County (Box 4, Folder 229)
  - Members, Patrick County, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 230)
  - Members, Washington County (Box 4, Folder 231)
  - Members and Officers, Lynchburg, 1910-1914 (Box 4, Folder 232)
  - Members, Norfolk (Box 4, Folder 233)
  - Members, Norfolk, with presidents of local leagues (Box 4, Folder 234)
  - Members, Petersburg, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 235)
  - Members, Richmond (Box 4, Folder 236)
  - Members, Officers, Possible Workers, Richmond, 1913-1917 (Box 4, Folder 237)
  - Membership roster, Richmond (Box 4, Folder 238)
  - Officers, Committee Assignments, 1913-1919 (Box 4, Folder 239)
  - Presidents of local leagues (Box 4, Folder 240)
  - Membership lists, Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 241)
  - News Bulletins, 1914-1915 (Box 4, Folder 242)
  - News Bulletins, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 243)
  - News Bulletins, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 244)
  - News Bulletins, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 245)
  - News Bulletins, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 246)
  - News Bulletins, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 247)
  - News Bulletins, nd (Box 4, Folder 248)
- Organization Records, Equal Suffrage League, Virginia, Petitions
  - Albemarle County (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - Alleghany County (Box 5, Folder 250)
  - Augusta County (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - Chesterfield County (Box 5, Folder 252)
  - Clarke County (Box 5, Folder 253)
  - Essex County (Box 5, Folder 254)
  - Fluvanna County (Box 5, Folder 255)
  - Grayson County (Box 5, Folder 256)
  - Greensville County (Box 5, Folder 257)
  - King George County (Box 5, Folder 258)
  - King William County (Box 5, Folder 259)
  - Lancaster County (Box 5, Folder 260)
  - Mecklenburg County (Box 5, Folder 261)
  - Nansemond County (Box 5, Folder 262)
  - Nottoway County (Box 5, Folder 263)
  - Powhatan County (Box 5, Folder 264)
  - Prince William County (Box 5, Folder 265)
  - Princess Anne County (Box 5, Folder 266)
  - Richmond County (Box 5, Folder 267)
  - Rockbridge County (Box 5, Folder 268)
  - Southampton County (Box 5, Folder 269)
  - Sussex County (Box 5, Folder 270)
  - Westmoreland County (Box 5, Folder 271)
  - Alexandria (Box 5, Folder 272)
  - Alexandria (Box 5, Folder 273)
  - Hampton (Box 5, Folder 274)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 275)
  - Pledgers, including list of officers for local leagues, 1915-1919 (Box 5, Folder 276)
  - Press releases, 1911-1920 (Box 5, Folder 277)
  - Press releases, nd (Box 5, Folder 278)
  - Questionnaire/interview responses on the suffrage question, General Assembly, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 279)
  - Resolutions, 1913-1920 (Box 5, Folder 280)
  - Resolutions, nd (Box 5, Folder 281)
  - Resolutions ending suffrage, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 282)
  - Memorandum book, Edith C. Cowles (Box 5, Folder 283)
  - Memorandum book, Edith C. Cowles, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 284)
  - Drafts, including essays, committee reports, speeches, correspondence, and Equal Suffrage League constitution (Box 5, Folder 285)
  - Drafts, including essays, committee reports, speeches, correspondence, and Equal Suffrage League constitution (Box 5, Folder 286)
- Equal Suffrage League, Newport News
  - Report, 1916-1917 (Box 5, Folder 287)
- Equal Suffrage League, Norfolk
  - Minutes, 1914-1915 (Box 5, Folder 288)
  - Recording secretary's book, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 289)
  - Reports, 1914-1920 (Box 5, Folder 290)
- Equal Suffrage League, Richmond
  - American Red Cross reports, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 291)
  - Essay contest, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 292)
  - Minutes, 1918-1919 (Box 5, Folder 293)
  - Reports, 1916-1918 (Box 5, Folder 294)
- Equal Suffrage League, Roanoke
  - Reports, nd (Box 5, Folder 295)
- University Suffrage League, Albemarle County
  - Reports, 1914-1917 (Box 5, Folder 296)
  - Expense accounts, Adele Clark, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 297)
  - Expense accounts, Eudora Ramsay, nd (Box 5, Folder 298)
  - Farmer's Educational and Cooperative Union of America, Resolution (Box 5, Folder 299)
  - Federation of Women's Clubs, Resolution (Box 5, Folder 300)
- League of Women Voters, Virginia
  - Bulletin, 1920-1930 (Box 5, Folder 301)
  - Conference, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 302)
  - Constitution, bylaws (Box 5, Folder 303)
  - Financial statements, 1920-1922 (Box 5, Folder 304)
  - General Assembly and Richmond city elections, 1921-1929 (Box 5, Folder 305)
  - Membership application (Box 5, Folder 306)
  - Membership lists, Norfolk and Richmond, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 307)
  - Press releases (Box 5, Folder 308)
  - Resolutions (Box 5, Folder 309)
- League of Women Voters, National
  - Ballot (Box 5, Folder 310)
  - Child Welfare Committee, recommendations (Box 5, Folder 311)
  - Committee concerning the legal status of women, recommendations (Box 5, Folder 312)
  - Committee on American citizenship, recommendations (Box 5, Folder 313)
  - Committee on food supply and demand, recommendations (Box 5, Folder 314)
  - Conference, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 315)
  - Newsletter, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 316)
  - Organization plan (Box 5, Folder 317)
  - Pledge, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 318)
  - Press releases (Box 5, Folder 319)
  - Reports, miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 320)
  - Suffrage school schedule 1917 (Box 5, Folder 321)
  - Women in industry department, report (Box 5, Folder 322)
- League of Women Voters, Norfolk
  - Minutes, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 323)
  - Financial (Box 5, Folder 324)
  - Questionnaire, nd (Box 5, Folder 325)
  - Voter registration records (Box 5, Folder 326)
- Legue of Women Voters, Richmond
  - Ballot, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 327)
  - Board of Directors minutes 1921 (Box 5, Folder 328)
  - Cookbook committee minutes, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 329)
  - Reports, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 330)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1920-1921 (Box 5, Folder 331)
- League of Women Voters, New York
  - Pyramid Plan (Box 5, Folder 332)
- Men's League for Women Suffrage
  - Membership lists, nd (Box 5, Folder 333)
- Men's Equal Suffrage League, Virginia
  - Resolutions, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 334)
- National American Woman Suffrage Association
  - Ballot (Box 5, Folder 335)
  - Bulletin, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 336)
  - Constitution (Box 5, Folder 337)
  - Essays, nd (Box 5, Folder 338)
  - Executive Council, recommendations (Box 5, Folder 339)
  - Press releases, 1914-1920 (Box 5, Folder 340)
  - Press releases, nd (Box 5, Folder 341)
  - Press releases, nd (Box 5, Folder 342)
  - Proclamation (Box 5, Folder 343)
- National Woman's Party, Norfolk
  - Minutes, nd (Box 5, Folder 344)
- National Women's Trade Union League
  - Press releases (Box 5, Folder 345)
- Equal Suffrage League, Virginia
  - Annual reports, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 346)
  - Legislative committee, General Assembly, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 347)
  - Meeting reports, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 348)
  - Membership lists, miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 349)
  - Minutes and officers, Richmond (Box 5, Folder 350)
  - Officers, committee assignments (Box 5, Folder 351)
  - Pledges (Box 5, Folder 352)
  - Fragments (Box 5, Folder 353)
- League of Women Voters, Virginia
  - Board of Directors minutes, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 354)
- Subject files
  - Child labor (Box 6, Folder 355)
  - Child labor (Box 6, Folder 356)
  - Civil Works Administration (Box 6, Folder 357)
  - Coordinate College for Women (Charlottesville, Va.), 1914 (Box 6, Folder 358)
- Equal Suffrage League, Virginia
  - Biographical sketches of members (Box 6, Folder 359)
  - Canvassing reports (Box 6, Folder 360)
  - Petitions, blank (Box 6, Folder 361)
  - Pledge cards (Box 6, Folder 362)
- League of Women Voters
  - Citizenship schools, 1921-1927 (Box 6, Folder 363)
  - Citizenship schools, 1921-1927 (Box 6, Folder 364)
  - Committee on the cause and cure of war, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 365)
  - National committee to secure rank for nurses, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 366)
- National American Woman Suffrage Association
  - Home and garden notes (Suffrage agriculture) (Box 6, Folder 367)
  - Public health (Virginia and Mississippi) (Box 6, Folder 368)
  - Theodore Roosevelt (Box 6, Folder 369)
  - Speeches, 1914-1924 (Box 6, Folder 370)
  - Speeches, nd (Box 6, Folder 371)
- Stationary
  - Equal Suffrage League (Box 6, Folder 372)
  - Equal Suffrage League (Box 6, Folder 373)
  - Richmond League of Women Voters (Box 6, Folder 374)
  - Virginia League of Women Voters (Box 6, Folder 375)
  - Virginia Women's Council of Legislative Chairman of State Organziations (Box 6, Folder 376)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 377)
- Suffrage materials, miscellaneous
  - Virginia (Box 6, Folder 378)
  - Non-Virginia (Box 6, Folder 379)
  - Suffrage plays (Box 6, Folder 380)
  - Suffrage poems, anecdotes (Box 6, Folder 381)
  - Suffrage songs and music (Box 6, Folder 382)
  - Ida Mae Thompson, personal papers (Box 6, Folder 383)
  - Jessie Townsend, personal papers (Box 6, Folder 384)
  - Jessie Townsend, personal papers, fragile (Box 6, Folder 385)
  - United States Department of the Interior, Office of Education (Box 6, Folder 386)
  - Lila Meade Valentine Memorial (Box 6, Folder 387)
  - Virginia Tech, Virginia's Defense is in Safe Farming, newsletter (Box 6, Folder 388)
  - Voter registration (Box 6, Folder 389)
  - Votes for women napkins (Box 6, Folder 390)
  - White supremacy and suffrage (Box 6, Folder 391)
  - Woodrow Wilson (Box 6, Folder 392)
- World War I
  - General (Box 6, Folder 393)
  - Virginia (Box 6, Folder 394)
  - Young Women's Christian Association, 1920-1921 (Box 6, Folder 395)
  - Calling cards (Box 6, Folder 396)
  - Card, Monumental church (Box 6, Folder 397)
- Postcards
  - Anti-suffrage (Box 6, Folder 398)
  - The Awakening (Box 6, Folder 399)
  - Bread and roses (Box 6, Folder 400)
  - Christmas (suffrage) (Box 6, Folder 401)
  - English (suffrage) (Box 6, Folder 402)
  - It can't be did (Box 6, Folder 403)
  - New Year's resolutions for suffragists, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 404)
  - No taxation without representation (Box 6, Folder 405)
  - Politics is not outside the home (Box 6, Folder 406)
  - The suffragist arousing her sisters (Box 6, Folder 407)
  - Valentine (suffrage) (Box 6, Folder 408)
  - Lila Meade Valentine, speech advertisements (Box 6, Folder 409)
  - Votes for women (Box 6, Folder 410)
  - Votes for women, A success (Box 6, Folder 411)
  - A Wish for 1915 (Box 6, Folder 412)
  - Woman's cause (Box 6, Folder 413)
  - Woman's hour (Box 6, Folder 414)
  - Photographic (Box 6, Folder 415)
  - Suffrage, miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 416)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 417)
  - Photogrpahic images (Box 6, Folder 418)
  - Ephemera (Box 6, Folder 419)
- Publications, Business Women's Equal Suffrage League
  - Pamphlet (Box 7, Folder 420)
  - Calendars (suffrage), 1910-1912 (Box 7, Folder 421)
  - College Equal Suffrage League (Box 7, Folder 422)
  - Congressional Union for Woman Suffrage (Box 7, Folder 423)
  - Dixie Suffragist (Box 7, Folder 424)
- Publications, Equal Suffrage League, Virginia
  - Booklets (Box 7, Folder 425)